added-value.com 2019-06-05

# Privacy Policy – Kantar Added Value

**Privacy Policy        Last updated:  23 May 2018**

Kantar Added Value (“We”) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, in connection with your use of our website at [www.added-value.com](http://www.added-value.com/), our mobile applications and any of our other online or mobile products, content and services (collectively, “Our Services”) will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

Information we collect from you

We collect and process the following data in connection with your use of Our Services:

  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on our website. We may also ask you for information when you report a problem with our Services.
  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
  * We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.
  * Details of your access to our Services including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access.

IP addresses

We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration. This is used to generate statistical data about our users’ access, use, browsing actions and patterns.

Cookies

Our Services use cookies to distinguish you from other users of Our Services and to remember you between visits. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you use Our Services and also allows us to improve our site.

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer’s hard drive.

In general, We use certain types of cookies in connection with Our Services:

  * to identify you as you use Our Services;
  * where relevant, to help us authenticate you as a subscriber and to give you access to your user profile;
  * to customize and personalize your experience of Our Services; and
  * to compile anonymous statistics about the use of Our Services.

These cookies do not contain any information that, in itself, personally identifies you and do not provide us with access to the rest of your device. We may, however, associate the information contained in cookies with personal information that you have provided to us separately.

More particularly, we use certain types of WordPress cookies.  Here is a list of the main cookies that we use on Our Services, and what each is used for.

**Cookie name** | **Cookie type** | **Purpose**  
---|---|---  
**WordPress 3.6**  
wordpress_[hash] | Session (with an adjustable duration)* – functional | On log-in, this cookie is used to store your authentication details. Its use is limited to the admin console area.  
wordpress_logged_in_[hash] | Session (with an adjustable duration)* – functional | After log-in, this cookie is used to indicate when you are logged in, and who you are, for most interface use.  
wp-settings-{time}-[UID] | Session (with an adjustable duration)* – functional | A few cookies of this type are set. The number on the end is your individual user ID from the users’ database table. This is used to customise your view of the admin interface, and possibly also the main site interface.  
* These cookies’ duration can be adjusted with the “auth_cookie_expiration” hook.  An example can be found at [what’s the easiest way to stop wp from ever logging me out](https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=http-3A__wordpress.stackexchange.com_questions_515_whats-2Dthe-2Deasiest-2Dway-2Dto-2Dstop-2Dwp-2Dfrom-2Dever-2Dlogging-2Dme-2Dout&d=DQMF-g&c=zdK58V2JKULZdB8nuBRpog&r=2hslGxWmtNnV-fQJ6myg2WZ7pJkOItU2sG61umCRYCQ&m=RAtRCWIs6akOjGY01yTJ0vcHOuM2dxnxBqIJlINv9FE&s=yNeSch8pPTfcKU-qR1IIbVKSOgk3OgjWfdcsH0NhEAc&e=). 

For further details on the WordPress 3.6 cookies (including the functions to set and remove such cookies), please see [http://codex.wordpress.org/WordPress_Cookies](https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=http-3A__codex.wordpress.org_WordPress-5FCookies&d=DQMF-g&c=zdK58V2JKULZdB8nuBRpog&r=2hslGxWmtNnV-fQJ6myg2WZ7pJkOItU2sG61umCRYCQ&m=RAtRCWIs6akOjGY01yTJ0vcHOuM2dxnxBqIJlINv9FE&s=KJUMG4QpqbvW8Cm0w_ynHj-nkzA9uIHGXKH-2u5UVQM&e=).  
  
**WordPress Commenters**  
comment_author | Persistent (with a duration of just under one year) – functional | When visitors comment on a blog, cookies are stored on their computer. This is purely a convenience, so that the visitor will not need to re-type all their information again when they want to leave another comment.  This first commenter cookie relates to the author.  
comment_author_email | Persistent (with a duration of just under one year) – functional | This second commenter cookie relates to the author’s email address.  
comment_author_url | Persistent (with a duration of just under one year) – functional | This third commenter cookie relates to the author’s url.  
  
We may introduce further types of cookie and/or similar technology from time to time to improve your experience of Our Services.  If We do so, We shall update the list above to note any further main cookies and/or similar technology used on Our Services.

If you require any further information on the cookies that We use, you can contact us as described in the **_How to contact us_** section below.

**Third-party cookies**.  Please note that our business partners’ or other sites that may be accessible via Our Services (such as web traffic analyzers and advertising networks) may also use cookies, over which We have no control.  These are likely to be analytical cookies and/or targeting cookies. You should check the privacy and cookies policies posted on the relevant third-party sites for further information on such cookies (including details of how to reject or delete such cookies).

Our Services also use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“ **Google** ”). Google Analytics uses cookies to help us analyze how users use Our Services. The information generated by Google’s cookies about your use of Our Services (including your IP address) is anonymous and will be sent to Google and held on Google’s servers in the USA in accordance with Google’s privacy policy (available at [http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/privacy/](https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=http-3A__www.google.co.uk_intl_en_privacy_&d=DQMF-g&c=zdK58V2JKULZdB8nuBRpog&r=2hslGxWmtNnV-fQJ6myg2WZ7pJkOItU2sG61umCRYCQ&m=RAtRCWIs6akOjGY01yTJ0vcHOuM2dxnxBqIJlINv9FE&s=_wxn80ijTKsd_Tf6pmJMOUiINaapnnf07sq9Y8oJJfE&e=)).

Our Services also allow the setting of two Google Maps cookies (and please refer to Google for further information on these):

**Cookie name** | **Cookie expiry** | **Domain** | **Typical content**  
---|---|---|---  
NID | 6 months | google.com | Specific key  
PREF | 2 years | google.com | Specific key  
  
Please note that Google may also transfer Google-held information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. We understand that Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google.

In addition, WPML uses two plug-ins to detect your current selected language:

_icl_visitor_lang

_icl_current_language

Also, Visited Cookie detects if you have visited the site and accepted cookies.

**Rejecting and deleting cookies**.  If you object to the use of cookies on Our Services, most browsers can be configured to alert you to their use or to enable you to reject browser-based cookies. Third parties may use certain special types of cookies (such as flash cookies) that cannot be disabled by configuring browsers, although other methods of preventing or managing such cookies may be available to you (such as via the relevant third-party settings panel). You can also delete cookies already stored on your device.

To learn how to reject or delete cookies, we recommend that you consult the “Help” function of your internet browser or, for a mobile phone, your handset manual. Further information on rejection and deletion of cookies is provided on [www.aboutcookies.org](https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=http-3A__www.aboutcookies.org_&d=DQMF-g&c=zdK58V2JKULZdB8nuBRpog&r=2hslGxWmtNnV-fQJ6myg2WZ7pJkOItU2sG61umCRYCQ&m=RAtRCWIs6akOjGY01yTJ0vcHOuM2dxnxBqIJlINv9FE&s=Zjky38Xv0_rf92gNbRVbBpbH19dR88PDds4WpcC039Q&e=).  For further information on managing behavioral advertising, please visit [www.youronlinechoices.com/uk](https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=http-3A__www.youronlinechoices.com_uk&d=DQMF-g&c=zdK58V2JKULZdB8nuBRpog&r=2hslGxWmtNnV-fQJ6myg2WZ7pJkOItU2sG61umCRYCQ&m=RAtRCWIs6akOjGY01yTJ0vcHOuM2dxnxBqIJlINv9FE&s=W5p2dQtXYJfzVL6NeNwvdmS2nnkbLWrDGiDMTXqnWTI&e=).

If, however, you decide to disable or delete any cookies, some parts or features of Our Services (especially interactive features) may not work properly. For some parts of Our Services, We may require you to uninstall or cease using the relevant applications, rather than have a poor experience from disabling cookies. Disabling or deleting cookies may also affect your ability to use other online or mobile sites.

Where we store your personal data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the United States (“US”) or the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the US or the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. If your personal data is transferred to, stored at or otherwise processed in a country or territory outside the US or the EEA, and that country or territory has not been recognized as providing an adequate level of data protection, we will put in place additional safeguards to protect your personal data, based on standard contractual clauses.  You can ask us to provide a copy of these clauses by using the contact details below.

KEEPING YOUR PERSONAL DATA SECURE

We will take reasonable steps to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Policy. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure server. We limit access to the information by our own employees, contractors, site service providers and those individuals who are authorized for the proper handling of such information. We request that our third party contractors and site service providers follow similar standards of security and confidentiality.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will take reasonable steps to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access.

Uses made of the information

We have listed below the ways in which we use your personal data.  We are also required by law to explain the legal basis for using your personal data, and this is also set out below.  The legal basis in each case is that we have your consent for the use of your personal data, or that we need to use your personal data in order to perform a contract with you, or that the use of your personal data is necessary for our (or third parties’) legitimate interests (in which case we will explain what those interests are).  Where we use your personal data with your consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.

  * To ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer (this is based on our legitimate interest in ensuring that our site is presented to you in the most effective way possible).
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes (this is based on your consent, which you may withdraw at any time).
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us (this is based on contractual necessity – we need to use your personal data to perform our contract with you).
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.
  * To notify you about changes to our service (this is based on our legitimate interest in keeping you informed about changes to our service).

We may also use your personal data, or permit selected companies within the Kantar Group of companies to use your personal data, to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you and we or they may contact you about these by mail or telephone.  This is based on our legitimate interest, or our group members’ legitimate interest, in providing you with information about our or their goods or services.

Disclosure of your information

We may disclose your personal data to any member of the Kantar Group of companies, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006. We may disclose your personal data to third parties:

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
  * If Kantar or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Kantar, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

HOW LONG WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We are required by law to keep your personal data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes for which we are using it.  The period for which we keep your personal data will be determined by a number of criteria, including the purposes for which we are using the information, the amount and sensitivity of the information, the potential risk from any unauthorized use or disclosure of the information, and our legal and regulatory obligations.

Your rights

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at privacy@Kantarconsulting.com.

You also have the following rights in relation to your personal data (some of these rights apply only in certain circumstances, and some of them vary according to the legal basis on which we are processing your data – please see above for further details):

  * The right to ask whether we’re processing your personal data and, if we are, to find out details of that processing (as well as obtaining a copy of your personal data).
  * The right to ask us to correct any personal data that we hold about you that’s inaccurate or incomplete.
  * The right to ask us to delete personal data that we hold about you.
  * The right to object to how we’re processing your personal data, and to ask us to restrict how we’re processing your personal data.
  * The right to have the personal data that you’ve provided to us provided to you in a structured and commonly-used electronic format.  You can also ask us to transfer your personal data directly to another company if that’s feasible.

If you’re not happy with how we’ve dealt with your personal data, we’d like a chance to put it right – please contact us at [privacy@kantarconsulting.com](mailto:privacy@kantarconsulting.com)

However, you have the right to complain to a supervisory authority – the authority for the UK is the Information Commissioner (www.ico.org.uk)].

LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

Changes to our privacy policy

This Policy was last updated on May 23, 2018. Any changes we may make to our Policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this Policy are welcomed and should be addressed to [privacy@kantarconsulting.com](mailto:privacy@kantarconsulting.com)

You can also contact our data protection officer (DPO), Gillie Abbotts-Jones, at [privacy@kantarconsulting.com](mailto:privacy@kantarconsulting.com)
